{
  "1" : {
    "front" : "How big is an average vineyard in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "Average vineyard in __Alsace__ is less than three hectares.\n\nVineyard holdings often spread throughout several vineyards.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace"]
  },
  "2" : {
    "front" : "Name the two dominant *négociant* houses in __Alsace__.",
    "back" : "__Hugel__ and __Trimbach__",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viniculture", "alsace"]
  },
  "3" : {
    "front" : "How much of __Alsace__ production is done by independent grower-producers?",
    "back" : "Approx. 20%\n\n80% of production in __Alsace__ are by *négociants* and *co-operatives*. The quality of co-operative wine is particularly high in __Alsace__.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viniculture", "alsace"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZob" : {
    "front" : "Describe the growing climate in __Alsace__.",
    "back" : "__Alsace__ has a cool *continental* climate.\n\nIt is one of the driest regions in France, and the lack of clouds result in hot summers and sunny, dry autumns.\n\nIts autumn season is longer than typical for this type of climate",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "climate", "alsace"]
  },
  "5" : {
    "front" : "What geographic features affect the climate in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "__Vosges__ mountains lie to the west of __Alsace__, protecting it from prevailing westerly, rain-bearing rains.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "geography", "alsace", "climate"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZod" : {
    "front" : "What geographic features contribute to the broad range of wine styles in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "__Alsace__ has a rich geological history, and therefore, a great variety of soils:\n\n* slopes - granitic, limestone, sandstone, clay, loam, and volcanic soils\n* plains - primarily alluvial",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "terroir", "alsace", "geography"]
  },
  "7" : {
    "front" : "How are vines trained in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "On __Alsace__ slopes, vines are trained low for maximum benefit from radiated heat, and are arranged to maximise sun exposure.\n\nOn the plains, vines are trained high on the plains to minimise the exposure to spring frosts.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace"]
  },
  "8" : {
    "front" : "What are the most important grape varieties grown in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "The most important varieties in __Alsace__ are:\n\n* *Riesling*\n* *Gewurztraminer*\n* *Pinot Gris*\n* *Muscat*\n* *Pinot Blanc*\n* *Sylvaner*\n* *Pinot Noir*",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "varietals", "alsace", "riesling", "gewurztraminer", "pinot_gris", "muscat", "pinot_blanc", "sylvaner", "pinot_noir"]
  },
  "9" : {
    "front" : "How long is the harvest season in __Alsace__ and why?",
    "back" : "Harvests in __Alsace__ start in mid-September and may last until end of November or into December.\n\nThis is because growers plant many different varieties, which ripen over a long period of time in the cool continental climate.",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace", "climate"]
  },
  "10" : {
    "front" : "What techniques do __Alsace__ producers employ to maximize pure flavours in their wines?",
    "back" : "* grapes are pressed in *pneumatic presses*\n* juice fermented in large, old oak casks\n* oak casks typically have thick tartrate deposits to prevent the wood from influencing the wine\n* many now use stainless steel vats with precise temperature control\n* *malolactic fermentation* is normally not used",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viniculture", "alsace"]
  },

  "-L576FEQTrF2txySBjIk" : {
    "front" : "Which grape varieties can be listed on __Alsace__ wine labels?",
    "back" : "Only *noble varieties* can be used (and listed) in *VT*, *SGN* and *Grand Cru* wines:\n\n* *Riesling*\n* *Gewurztraminer*\n* *Pinot Gris*\n* *Muscat*\n\nOther varietally labelled wines: *Pinot Blanc*, *Pinot Noir* and *Sylvaner*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "varietals", "alsace", "law", "riesling", "gewurztraminer", "pinot_gris", "muscat", "pinot_noir", "pinot_blanc"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZof" : {
    "back" : "The appellation system in __Alsace__ is very simple - there are only two ACs for still wine:\n\n1. *Alsace AC* (70%+ producion of __Alsace__)\n2. *Alsace Grand Cru AC* (51 vineyards with *Grand Cru* status)\n\nStill wines can be further classified as:\n* *Vendange Tardive* (VT) late harvest wines\n* *Sélection de Grains Nobles* (SGN) *botrytis* influenced sweet wines",
    "front" : "How are still wines classified in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "botrytis", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "11" : {
    "back" : "*Vendange Tardive* (VT) - late harvest wines made from the four noble varieties.\n\n*Riesling* and *Muscat* must have sugar ripeness capable of reaching *14% abv*; *Pinot Gris* and *Gewurztraminer* to *15.3% abv*.\n\nGrapes for best wines will have undergone *passerillage* and some have influence of *botrytis*.\n\nStyles can vary from dry to medium sweet and there is no requirement to indicate wine sweetness.",
    "front" : "What does *VT* mean in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "sweet_wine", "botrytis", "passerillage", "riesling", "muscat", "pinot_gris", "gewurztraminer"]
  },
  "12" : {
    "back" : "*Sélection de Grains Nobles* (SGN) - 'selection of nobly rotten grapes' made from the four noble varieties.\n\n*Riesling* and *Muscat* must have sugar ripeness capable of reaching *16.4% abv*; *Pinot Gris* and *Gewurztraminer* to *18.2% abv*.",
    "front" : "What does *SGN* mean in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "sweet_wine", "botrytis", "riesling", "muscat", "pinot_gris", "gewurztraminer"]
  },
  "13" : {
    "back" : "*Vendange Tardive* (VT) at 14% - 15.3% abv roughly corresponds to a ripe *Auslese*\n\n*Sélection de Grains Nobles* (SGN) (16.4% - 18.2% abv) roughly translates to a full-bodied *Beerenauslese*",
    "front" : "What does __Alsace__ *VT* and *SGN* roughly translate to in the *Prädikat* system?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "sweet_wine", "pradikat", "germany", "austria"]
  },
  "-L576FERZq9sguvoAZoh" : {
    "back" : "__Alsace__ wines can be high in alcohol (14%+ abv) and retain an element of sweetness due to its long, sunny, dry summers and autumns - ideal for grapes to acquire high levels of sugar ripeness.\n\nDuring fermentation, the yeast will be overcome by the alcohol before all the sugar is fermented.\n\nDry conditons also mean *passerillage* is more common than *botrytis*, giving wines a *dried fruit* character rather than typical *botrytis* *honey* and *orange marmalade* characters.",
    "front" : "How are off-dry and sweet still white wines produced in __Alsace__?\n",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viniculture", "winestyle", "alsace", "passerillage", "botrytis", "sweet_wine"]
  },
  "14" : {
    "back" : "Terms such as *Réserve Personnelle* and *Cuvée Spéciale* have no legal status.\n\nProducers use these statements in an attempt to distinguish different qualities of wine produced.",
    "front" : "What do label terms like *Réserve Personnelle* and *Cuvée Spéciale* mean in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace"]
  },
  "14" : {
    "back" : "3\n\nStill wines:\n\n* *Alsace AC*\n* *Alsace Grand Cru AC*\n\nSparkling wines:\n* *Crémant d'Alsace AC*",
    "front" : "How many *ACs* are there in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "sparkling"]
  },
  "15" : {
    "back" : "*Alsace Grand Cru* wines must:\n\n* be from one of 51 vineyards with *Grand Cru* status\n* conform to stricter production and maximum yield criteria\n* reach higher sugar ripness levels\n* be made from a single noble variety\n\nExceptions are:\n\n* __Kaefferkopf__ and __Altenberg de Bergheim__ allow blending\n* __Zotzenberg__ allows *Sylvaner*",
    "front" : "What are the requirements for an *Alsace Grand Cru AC* wine?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "grand_cru"]
  },
  "16" : {
    "front" : "Describe a high quality __Alsace__ wine.",
    "back" : "Best __Alsatian__ wines (with the exception of VT and SGN) are dry, full bodied, with a notable spicy flavour in addition to its pure fruit flavours.\n\n*Botrytis* can influence even some dry wines, softening the fruit and adding additional spicy complexity and viscosity.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "botrytis"]
  },
  "17" : {
    "front" : "Describe a typical blended wine from __Alsace__.",
    "back" : "Blended __Alsace__ wines are typically made from juice not selected for varietal wines and are light in body and does not have the *Alsatian* spicy character.\n\nThey can be labelled *Edelzwicker* (noble blend) or *Gentil*, or carry the producer's brand name.\n\nHigh quality blends from *Grand Cru* vineyards exist but are extremely rare.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace"]
  },
  "17" : {
    "front" : "How do __Alsace__ *Riesling* differ from *German* styles?",
    "back" : "*Alsatian* *Riesling* are *full bodied*, *dry*, *medium* to *medium+* alcohol, *high acidity*, and obvious *flinty* *mineral* characters.\n\nCompared to *German* *Riesling* that are *light bodied* and *medium-sweet*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "varietal", "riesling"]
  },
  "16" : {
    "front" : "Describe __Alsace__ *Gewurztraminer* wines.",
    "back" : "The skin of *Gewurztraminer* (spelt without umlaut in France) has a light ping tinge that gives a *golden colour* to the wine.\n\nThey tend to be *full bodied* with a *rich oily texture*, *medium to low acidity*, *high alcohol*, and a pungent *aromatic spicy nose* of *lychees*, *roses*, and *sweet spices*.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "varietal", "gewurztraminer"]
  },
  "17" : {
    "front" : "Which __Alsace__ wine style pairs well with Chinese and Thai dishes?",
    "back" : "*Alsatian* *Gewurztraminer* VTs have an exaggerated and exotic fruit character that complements many Chinese and Thai dishes, as well as smoked fish and strong cheeses.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "easy",
    "tags" : ["fr", "pairing", "alsace", "gewurztraminer"]
  },
  "18" : {
    "front" : "What is a *Tokay d'Alsace*?",
    "back" : "*Pinot Gris* in __Alsace__ had previously been labelled as *Tokay d'Alsace*, then as *Tokay Pinot Gris*.\n\nThe EU required any reference to *Tokay* to be dropped to avoid confusion with the famous *Hungarian* sweet wine.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "law", "alsace", "pinot_gris"]
  },
  "19" : {
    "front" : "Describe the differences between __Alsace__ *Pinot Gris* and *Gewurztraminer* styles.",
    "back" : "*Pinot Gris* are rich, *full-bodied*, and *high in alcohol*. They have similar *golden* colour to *Gewurztraminer* and have equally *rich texture*, but tend to be less aromatic.\n\n*Pinot Gris* have *pronounced* flavour intensity of *fresh and dried fruits*, and a *smoky*, *honeyed* character.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "pinot_gris"]
  },
  "20" : {
    "front" : "What is contributing to the decline in __Alsace__ *Muscat* production?",
    "back" : "*Muscat* grapes are prone to *coulure* and *rot* and produces very inconsistent yields.\n\nIt now accounts for less than 3% of vineyard area in __Alsace__ even though it is considered a *noble* variety.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace", "varietal", "muscat"]
  },
  "21" : {
    "front" : "Which grape varieties are used to produce sparkling wines in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "*Pinot Blanc* and *Auxerrois*\n\nA wine labelled as *Pinot Blanc* will be a blend of the two varities; labelled as *Auxerrois* will be a pure varietal wine.\n\nGrown in the fertile soils of the plains, they (combined) now account for over 20% of plantings in __Alsace__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace", "pinot_blanc", "auxerrois", "sparkling"]
  },
  "22" : {
    "front" : "Describe an __Alsace__ *Pinot Noir*.",
    "back" : "__Alsace__ *Pinot Noir* are lighter and has less concentration than a __Burgundy__ *Pinot Noir*, and is best as a light fruity red or a *rosé*.\n\nSome winemakers are producing more substantial wines with new oak flavours.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "normal",
    "tags" : ["fr", "winestyle", "alsace", "pinot_noir"]
  },
  "23" : {
    "front" : "How much area under vine are allocated to non-noble varieties in __Alsace__?",
    "back" : "* *Pinot Blanc* and *Auxerrois* - over 20%\n* *Sylvaner* - 9%\n* *Pinot Noir* - almost 10%",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "status" : "active",
    "difficulty" : "hard",
    "tags" : ["fr", "viticulture", "alsace", "pinot_blanc", "auxerrois", "sylvaner", "pinot_noir"]
  },
}
